Papan Manna

Application Developer

Kolkata, West Bengal (+91) 6294284798 mannapapan.r@gmail.com My Website

Professional Summary

Software Professional having 2+ years of experience in software development including design, testing, release.

Experience in Android Application development using Java and Kotlin. Besides Experience on iOS development using Swift and XCode. Self motivated and fast learner and seeking a new opportunity that will allow me to further expand on these skills.

EXPERIENCE

Geotech Infoservices Pvt Ltd, Kolkata - Software Engineer

July 2018 - PRESENT

Working in Geotech as an Android Application Developer. Besides I have worked in all phases of Development in various technologies like Swift, Javascript, PHP, Symfony etc.

Geotech Infoservices Pvt Ltd, Kolkata - Trainee Software Engineer

February 2018 - May 2018

Learned the basic methodology of software development, work process and basic of many core technologies like php, Javascript, Ajax, jQuery etc.

EDUCATION

Meghnad Saha Institute Of Technology, Kolkata - B. Tech

2014 - 2018

I have pursued my graduation degree in Computer Science and Engineering degree with 86% marks.

Midnapore Collegiate School, Midnapore - Higher Secondary Education

2012 - 2014

I have pursued my Higher Secondary degree with 84% marks.

Akchara Deshbandhu High School, Midnapore - Secondary Education

2007 - 2012

I have pursued my Secondary degree with 86% marks.

PROJECTS

Real Fantasy Teams

About Project - Users can create dream fantasy teams for the best European Leagues. Check this <u>Play Store link</u>.

My Role - Developed Android application using java

Experiences -

- Developed core features e.g team creation, change formation, live point update, in-app subscriptions etc using Java.
- Integrate RxAndroid in this project. Integrate various payment gateway e.g Paytm, Google pay etc.
- Taken care of the security concerns e.g Code obfuscation, Local Data Encryption etc.

AXA IN (Conneqtech)

About Project - This app grants users a near real-time 24/7 insight in his/her bike's current location and whereabouts, even if it's not riding. Check this <u>Playstore link</u>.

My Role - Developed Android application using Kotlin and RxJava

Experiences -

- Developed many features e.g live bike tracking, create Geofences on MapView etc using Kotlin.
- Integrate Redux for better state maintaining.
- Customize UI, theme and amazing animations.

• Bergh Brandscheidingen

About Project - This app grants users to track the status of fire resistance tools inside the building. Check this <u>Playstore link</u>.

My Role - Developed and maintained Android application using Java.

Experiences -

- Developed offline caching and server syncing mechanism using Realm
 Database and Retrofit.
- Developed other features e.g image upload, add fire partition etc.
- Optimize code and upgrade leaflet version for better user experiences.

Rommtech Smart Bins

About Project - The aim of this project is to find a solution by using smart dustbins. It employs an Ultrasonic Sensor to prevent overflow of garbage from the dustbin.

My Role - Developed iOS application using Swift.

Experiences -

 Developed this application from scratch using Swift and have used many more core components like UIKit, MapKit, UITableView, Alamofire for networking etc.

NNEK

About Project - Financial management project in Europe.

My Role - Developed some functionality using php, symfony.

Experiences -

- From this project I have learned about symfony framework, doctrine, concept of CMS, cron job, swiftmailer etc.

Stay Home

About Project - This is one of my personal projects. The aim of this project is citizens can apply for online passes to go outside in COVID-19 pandemic lockdown.

My Role - Developed Android Application using Java.

SKILLS

- **Programming Languages -** Java, Kotlin, Swift, JavaScript, Php, jQuery
- **Networking -** Computer Networks
- Course Subjects Data structure and algorithm, Database management system,
 Operating system.